如果你是个普通人
If you're a normal person
死亡是你人生中少数的能指望的事之一
One of the few things you can count on in life is death.
-你好 -这玩意儿太棒了
-Hello. -These are amazing.
这些全都是关于医学的
They're--They're all about the medicine.
这里面没有私人恩怨
I mean...there's like no personal crap
没涉及到男朋友或者感情
No talk about boyfriends or feelings.
她甚至很少提你
She hardly even mentions you.
是啊 多谢你告诉我
Yes, thank you for pointing that out.
她怎么写她一动不动的
What about when she held the retractor
握着牵开器整整六个小时的
for six hours without moving?
但你要是个外科医生
But if you're a surgeon...
这唯一的指望也会被带走
Even that comfort is taken away from you.
他们就像我从来都没有的哈利波特魔书一样
They're like the harry potter books I never had.
你有没有读到她为一个三周大的婴儿
Hey, did you read the part when she did the pyloric stenosis
做幽门狭窄手术那段
On the 3-Week-Old baby?
外科医生欺骗死神
Surgeons cheat death.
我们延后并杜绝死亡
We prolong it, we deny it.
顶住 他心室颤动 调到300
Hold on. He's in v-Fib. Charge to 300.
退后
Clear.
加到360 退后
Up to 360. Clear.
我们始终在挑战 驱赶死神
We stand and defiantly give death the finger.
他行了 走吧
He's good. Let's go.
你们迟到了 她得去技能实验室
Hey, you're late. She has skills lab.
早上好 克里斯蒂娜 才过了几分钟
Good morning, Cristina. It feels like minutes.
待会见
See you later?
不行 不行 塔克
No no.Tucker.
我没说我不去咨询婚姻顾问
I did not say I won't do the marriage counseling.
我是说我早上不能去
I'm saying I can't do it in the mornings again.
我上班已经迟到了20分钟
I'm now 20 minutes late for work.
好吧 我今晚见你
O-Okay. I'll see you tonight.
婚姻顾问 你们的事儿怎么样了
Marriage counseling-- How's that going?
你刚听到我们为了婚姻顾问的事吵架
You just heard us arguing about the marriage counseling.
你说能怎么样了
How do you think it's going?
不是吧 你今天要给我的病人
No. You're doing a craniotomy
罗斯玛丽 波得 做开颅手术
On my patient Rosemary Bullard today.
你现在得清醒了
Now are you gonna be awake for that
不然你就要把呵欠打到人家脑袋里了
Or will you be yawning into her brain?
梅瑞狄斯害的我一晚上没怎么睡
Meredith kept me up most of the night.
我可不想听你们的房内事
I don't want to hear about your dirty nasty
她和克里斯蒂娜煲电话粥
Talking on the phone with Cristina.
他们妨碍你睡觉了 你说选杨还是我了吗
Aww. And they stole your sleep? Did you say Yang goes or I go?
-我可赢不了 -她们俩是一伙的
-I don't think I'd win that one. -Those two come as a set.
你从现在起得认清形势了
You should know that by now.
以前她还有伯克 伯克帮得上忙
Before she had Burke. Burke helped.
-是啊 -我觉得婚姻顾问有帮助的
-True. -I think counseling's a good move.
艾蒂逊和我就咨询过
Addison and I did counseling.
可你紧接着就离了婚啊
Right before you got divorced!
女士们先生们 容我向你们介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to introduce...
斯坦 一个艺术品
Stan.A state-Of-The-Art,
仿真病人模拟器
computerized patient simulator.
斯坦可以在导气管处理
Stan can educate you in airway management
外伤评估和处理方面训练你们
Trauma assessment and care.
他有呼吸 有脉搏 有意识
He breathes, he pulsates, he seizes
他会出血 分泌 还会说话
He hemorrhages, he secretes and he speaks.
你好 斯坦
Hello, Stan.
你好 医生 我觉得不舒服
Hello doctor. I'm not feeling well.
斯坦会告诉你们他的需求
Stan will tell you what he needs
而且他比起一般的病人更好说话
And he's more forgiving than most patients.
就算你害死了他 他会活过来
You kill him, he'll keep coming back for more.
大家伙好好的利用他
So make good use of him people.
我们现在要给机器人做手术了
We're operating on robots now?
-要不还是用猪吧 -是啊 用人也行啊
-Can we please go back to pigs? -Yeah, what about people?
主任会决定你们中的一个
when the chief decides which one of you
可以第一个做主刀手术
Gets to do the first solo surgery
-你们得好好准备 -等等 你刚说主刀手术
-You'll want to be ready. -Wait, did you just say solo surgery?
就一个 他会怎么挑
Just one of us? And how is he gonna pick one of us?
我既不知道会怎么挑
I do not know what it will be.
也不知道什么时候挑
I do not know when it will be.
我只知道赢的人得准备
I do know that the winner should be prepared
做任何外科手术
To do any surgical procedure
还能选一个实习医生做辅助
And will choose one intern to scrub in.
因此练好你的技能 让自己胜出
So practice your skills, impress your attendings
别丢我的脸就行了
And just do not make me look stupid.
格蕾 斯蒂文斯 你们跟翰 杨去急诊
Uh, Grey, Stevens.You're with Hahn. Yang, the pit.
克莱夫和欧麦利 你们今天在实验室练习
Karev and O'malley, you're skills lab today
-你们今天挨到去了解 -我要了
So you can take turns getting to know-- Dibs!
-是我的 -我胸口很疼
-Mine! -I am having chest pain.
很明显
So just to be clear
我们今天没机会开腔了
We are not cracking open any chests today?
是的 斯蒂文斯
No, Stevens.
只不过主刀手术就要来了
It's just that with the solo surgery coming up
我们想能做一个好点的外科手术之类的
We were kinda hoping to be on a cool surgical something
够了 我不想再听了
Right, I'm gonna stop you right there.
听着 我跟病人没什么接触 但我喜欢这个人
Listen, I don't get attached to patients, but I like this guy.
我花了近两年的时间
And I have spent almost two years
给他们家带来希望后又让他们失望
Giving his family hope and then taking it away.
这个手术能为他等来另一个移植器官
This procedure can buy him time until he can get
挣到一些时间
Another shot at a transplant.
-我们必须确保它成功 行不 -当然
-So we need to make sure it works, okay? -Absolutely.
-当然 -你们对病例已经熟悉了吧
-Of course. -You've familiarized yourself with the case?
是的 米歇尔 诺利斯 44岁 男性
Yeah, Michael Norris-- 44-Year-Old male
患有先天性心肌肥大病
With congenital hypertrophic cardiomyopathy
在西雅图伯斯医院治疗失败
Who has failed medical treatment at Seattle pres.
他一直在等一个心脏移植
He's been waiting on a heart transplant
曾差点就获得了机会
Since narrowly missing out on one
-在5月14日 200.. -等等
On may 14th of two thousand-- Wait wait.
-怎么了 -哪年的5月14日?
-What? -May 14th what?
怎么了
What?
那是 那是丹尼的心脏
That's... that's Denny's heart.
那是我为丹尼偷的心脏
That's the heart I stole for Denny.
我要你勾引克里斯蒂娜·杨上床
I need you to have sex with Cristina Yang.
早上好
Good morning.
转移她 吸引她
Yeah. Distract her. Engage her.
除了打电话给我女朋友和吵醒我之外
Give her something to do after midnight
让她在午夜过后有事可做
Besides call my girlfriend and wake me up.
杨? 不行不行 太严肃 死板 无趣
Yang? No. No, too serious, humorless, unFun--
-不合我胃口 -杨应该合你的胃口
-Not my type. -Yang should be your type.
她认真 聪明 难懂
She's intense, intelligent, complicated.
她就像纯麦威士忌
She's like a single malt scotch
你以前是吃大桶啤酒的
And you're used to beer bongs.
凯丽·托瑞斯可不是大桶啤酒
Callie Torres is no beer bong.
你知道么 等等 我懂了
Oh, you know, wait a minute.I get it.
你觉得你没机会上手
You don't think you have a shot.
你说得没错
You're probably right.
我有机会
Oh, I have a shot.
那就试一把 就当帮我
Then try it, as a favor.
不 我又不是你的种马
No.I'm not your stud horse.
-你不能指挥我跟谁上床 -你搞了我老婆
-You can't just, just tell me who to sleep. -You slept with my wife.
好吧 我试试
Yeah, I'll give it a shot.
好了 很好 对的
Okay, good.Right.
瞧那
Oh, look at that.
你们是在吸毒?
Are you guys shooting drugs?
-我的天 -不 我们在练习静脉输液
-Oh, my god. -No.We're practicing I.V.S.
-我们还能怎么学 -杨从来不让我们干活
-How else are we supposed to learn? -Yang never lets us do anything.
所以你们就在彼此身上练习?
So you're practicing on each other.
我们在贝勒大学也这样 没事的
We did it at Baylor. It's cool.
有事的 这太不像话了
No, it's not cool. It's crazy.
这简直就像恐怖地下室一样
It's like creepy-Basement crazy.
-别 别告诉别人 -她不会说的
-D-Don't tell anyone. She won't tell.
-别担心 她不会说的 -下一个我
-Don't worry. She won't tell. -I'm next.
来吧 好的
Come on. All right.
亨特医生 有时间么
Dr Hunt.Got a second?
一会就有事了 说吧
It's about to get a little loud in here, sir, but shoot.
听着 我们准备奖励一位
listen, we're getting ready to award
第二年实习生一个主刀手术
The first solo surgery to a second-Year resident.
我要你选人
I want your take.
不明身份的男性 35岁左右
Uh-- Unidentified male mid-30s
失去脉搏
Lost vitals in the field
电击后窦性心搏过速
Shocked him back into sinus tach.
双手骨折 骨盆不稳定
Possible fractures in both arms, unstable pelvis.
好了 三下 一 二 三
Okay, on.three, Two, three.
好的 来
Good go.
打开右心室监测仪 腹部僵硬
Open right tib/fib rigid abdomen.
-这男人怎么了? -在高速立交上发现他的
-What doesn't this guy have? Found him under a freeway overpass.
警察认为是有人把他扔那的
Cops think someone threw him over.
在把他揍了半死之后?
After they beat him half to death?
那个单独外科手术是个比赛么?
So it's a contest, the solo surgery?
你是新来的 你跟他们没私交
You have fresh eyes. You don't know them personally.
也没恩怨 感情之类的
You don't have any history any relationship.
-这样的情况这里很少有 -我考虑下
-That perspective is rare here. -I'll give it some thought.
韦伯医生 我在想
Oh, Dr.Webber, I was just wondering
想到那个主刀手术 我认为
Regarding the solo surgery, I presume it's gonna be
应该是一个普通的外科手术吧
A general surgery?
-我想做好准备 -该知道的时候你会知道的
-I just wanted to be prepared. -You'll know when you all know.
还有件事 我急诊室记录显示
And one more thing, if my E.R. Reports are right
你连着工作了三天
You've been working for three days straight.
-你什么时候睡觉的? -你是对每个人都记录
When do you sleep? You keep tabs on all your attendings
-还是只针对新来的? -他的静脉破裂了
-Or just the new guys? His I.V. Blew.
-杨 他需要立刻插管 -知道 我正在做
-Yang, he needs that access now. -Yes, I'm doing it, sir.
-要是你把这放进去他能多撑会
This will buy him some time until you get that line in.
要是你少担心怎么去赢比赛
If you were less worried about winning contests
你可能早做好了
You might have thought of it.
这么说来 你们要令我心脏病发作
So you're...gonna give me a, a heart attack, literally?
专业术语叫酒精烧蚀
it's a technique called alcohol ablation
通过插入你大腿动脉的导管
through a catheter in your femoral artery.
翰医生会直接向你的心脏内注入酒精
Dr.Hahn will inject ethanol straight into your heart.
酒精会烧死它所触及的细胞
The alcohol will incinerate any tissue cells it touches.
斯蒂文斯医生
Dr.Stevens?
我们会将你心室中
w-We're gonna be burning away
导致阻碍你摄入氧气
The muscle in your ventricle that's
的肌肉烧死
Blocking your ability to get oxygen.
如果我们成功了
If we're successful
你会立马觉得如释重负 所以
You should feel immediate relief, so...
我就能呼吸了吗?
Just like that, I'll... be able to breathe?
就是这样
Just like that.
-他手术时不能睡着么? -恐怕不行
-And he can't be asleep during the procedure? -I'm afraid not.
斯蒂文斯医生会要求你咳嗽
Dr. Stevens here will be asking you to cough
吸气和呼气
Inhale and exhale.
来瞧瞧我有没有死了?
And checking to see if I'm dead yet?
麦克 别这样
Mike stop.
那可是心脏病发作啊
I mean, it...it is a heart attack right?
这是个危险的手术
It's a dangerous procedure
但我们也能监测和掌控这个手术
But it's one that we can monitor and control.
如果你不做
And if you don't have it
你下次遇到心脏病发的时候
The next heart attack you have--
-就是你最后一次 -置我于死地
-And you will have one-- -Will kill me.
答应我你会让我醒着 我
Promise you'll keep me awake? I
我可不想死
I don't want to miss this.
在麦克去手术室之前
I want Mike's latest echo and angio
我要再看下他最新的回波和心血管造影
Before he goes to the cath lab.
-你是不是怕了? -什么? 为什么?
-Are you freaking out? -What? Why?
-你觉得我会么 -这个人住在丹尼的病房
-Do you think I should be? -This patient... in Denny's old room?
今天会回想起丹尼很多次 伊兹
It's a lot of Denny for one day, iz.
是很多 很多
It is a lot. A lot.
你也觉得对丹尼的回忆太多了?
Is it a lot of Denny for you too?
我是说 你想到关于多少丹尼的事?
I mean, how much Denny are you experiencing?
伊兹 你能做到的
Iz, you can do this.
我的疼痛加剧 我的疼痛加剧
My pain is getting worse. My pain is getting worse.
我讨厌这个
I hate this.
对着这塑料人练习
I'm not gonna win the solo surgery
-我肯定赢不了主刀手术 -你才不会赢
-Practicing on plastic man. -You're not gonna win the solo surgery
-你本来就烂 -你对病人的态度才叫烂
-Because you suck. -Your bedside manner is what sucks.
什么 你刚说什么
What? What did you say?
科技真是太神奇了
Ain't technology amazing?
死去吧 我要去练习医学了
Screw this. I'm gonna practice medicine.
你继续在这玩你的娃娃吧
You go ahead and play with your doll.
怎么了 被人说两句就怕了?
What's the matter, scared of a little education?
你真棒
you are so awesome
你真
you are so--
不不不不 斯坦
No! No! No! No! Stan!
一个人要做过什么才会被揍成这样
What does a guy have to do to get a beating this bad?
也许他醒过来以后会告诉我们
Maybe he'll tell us when he wakes up.
希望他可以坚持到那时候
Well let's hope he makes it that long.
3号 这些送交化验 然后去趟停尸房
Uh three run these to the lab and then go by the morgue
然后拿张无名尸体登记表
And get the forms for an unclaimed body.
他需要做胸管 不是吗?
He's gonna need a chest tube right?
因为主刀手术就要到了 我只是希望
Because I was just hoping--With the solo surgery coming up--
主刀手术是要到了 你更要给我留下好印象
With the solo surgery coming up your job is to impress me.
-快去吧 -杨医生 主刀手术是要到了
-So go. -Dr. Yang with the solo surgery coming up
你更要给我留下好印象
Your job is to impress me.
你已经在安排这个人死后的程序了
You are planning for this man's death
-而我还在尽力抢救 -我只是做好准备 抱歉
-While I am fighting for his life. -I was trying to be prepared. I'm sorry.
我不需要道歉 我只需要一名医生 尽职些吧
I can't use sorry. I could use a doctor. Be one.
你的转移瘤
The kind of metastases you have
可能导致自发性出血
Are prone to spontaneous bleeding.
所以手术风险相当大
So there are considerable risks to the surgery.
你是说这次的手术可能更冒险
Are you saying this one might be dicier?
可能更冒险
Might be a little dicier?
比之前的手术更冒险
Much dicier than previous surgeries.
我想说明白
I want to be clear.
不切除肿瘤你还可以活几个月
You can live with this tumor for months if not longer.
不 不要这样活着
Not--Not like this.
不要这么痛苦的活着
Not feeling this bad.
我明白风险是必然存在的
I understand that risks are part of the package.
所以你们这些医生让我一眼花
That's why you people make me go cross-Eyed
就签协议
Signing all these forms.
你在签不抢救协议
You're signing a "do not resuscitate" order?
-如果我的时间到了 -她不想靠机器维持生命
-If it's my time to go -She doesn't want to be on a life support kind of thing.
她讨厌那样
She'd hate that.
我只是讨厌那样呆躺着 我不想那样
I'd just hate lying around like that. I don't want that.
好的
Okay.
再见 亲爱的
Good-Bye darling.
再见 我的爱人
Good-Bye love.
不好意思 我们 我们每次都这样
Oh sorry. We... we do this every time.
她签协议 我们吻别
She signs the paper we kiss good-Bye
手术过后 我们再相聚
And then after the surgery we say hello again.
听起来是个仪式
Ll that sounds like a plan to me.
你先休息 我们就回来送你去手术
You rest up. We'll be bringing you up soon.
好的
Okay.
这真是婚姻的神圣境界
That there is the holy grail of marriage.
令人渴求
Mm. Something to aspire to.
怎么处置他们
What happens to them?
你签字 主治医生签字
You sign the attending signs
粉色复页夹进病历里
Pink copy goes in his chart.
不 我 我 我是说尸体 无名尸
No i-I-I mean the bodies the--The unclaimed bodies.
他们怎么办
What happens to them?
如果一段时间后依旧无人认领
Well if they remain unclaimed for a certain amount of time
-没有经过保持液处理的将被火化 -处理
-They're cremated--The ones that haven't been preserved. -Preserved?
用来做医学研究 大体解剖 外科研究
For medical research-- Gross anatomy surgical study--
之类的
That sort of thing.
给医科学生用
For like med students?
没错 医科学生
Exactly. For med stu-Students.
用来练手
To practice on?
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
感谢大家的到来
Um... thank you all for being here.
我很感激这个学习机会
I appreciate the opportunity to learn
你们的去世我感到很遗憾
And I'm sorry you had to die.
器具托盘
Oh uh uh instrument trays.
-保持积压 有脉搏了 -应改赶快送他去手术
-Hold compressions. We got a rhythm. -We've got to get him up to surgery.
血都渗出夹板了
He's bleeding through his leg splint.
主任让我从第二年住院医生中选择
So the chief asked me to watch the second years
主刀手术医生
For the solo surgery.
-你觉得该选谁 -他们可是形形色色
-What's your take as a class? -They're a mixed bag.
杨很优秀
Yang's very good.
她很坚强 她会成为一个心脏科权威
She's uh hard-Core. She'll be a cardio god.
-实际上她是我的室友 -斯蒂文斯呢
-She's my roommate actually. -And Stevens?
她很聪明 擅长与病人相处
She's smart good with patients
据说非常有同情心
Very compassionate... supposedly.
我和我前夫没离婚时他们就上床了
She did sleep with my ex-Husband while we were still married.
-知道吗 我对纯医学的部分更感兴趣 -没错
-You know what? I'm more interested in the doctor part. -Right.
那当然
Yeah. Obviously. Of course.
新的扫描结果 很好
New scans. good
脾脏囊下有血肿
There's a splenic subcapsular hematoma--
我自己会看 去写病历
I can look. Go update his chart.
杨医生 你呼我
Dr. Yang you paged me?
是的 病人在一号外伤室
Uh yeah patient trauma one.
你呼我来做会诊
Aw you paged me for a consult?
-我本来期待是你想见我 -没错
-I was hoping you wanted to see me. -I did.
病人鼻骨颧骨粉碎
Uh uh the patient has a shattered nose and cheekbones
左下腭骨骨折
And a fractured left mandible.
一号外伤室
Trauma one.
好的 麦克 导管接好了
Okay Mike the catheters are in.
-要注射了 -好
-It's time to inject. -Yeah.
好 抓紧了 斯蒂文斯请过来
Okay just hold tight. Stevens over here please.
我之所以选你跟进这个病人
I specifically chose you for this case
是因为你擅长和病人沟通
Because you connect well with patients.
是没错 但是这一点
Um... yeah that's actually
却是我被告知应当改正的
Something I've been told to work on not doing.
麦克需要你与他交流
Mike needs you talking to him.
他很害怕 他脉搏加速了
He's scared his pulse is elevating.
-快去 -好吧
-Step up. -Okay.
麦克
Hey mike.
你表现不错
You're doing great.
会出现一点灼烧感
You're gonna feel a little bit of burning.
然后我
Well then we get--Oh!
来了 天啊
Oh there it is. Oh god.
不要动 尽量平躺
Try not to move. Um try--Try to lay still
麦克 呼气
Mike and try to breathe.
停下来 快停下来
Make it stop. Make it stop.
麦克 我们不能停 很快就结束了
Mike we can't stop but it's gonna end soon
-坚持住 -斯蒂文斯 和他说话 -对不起
-So just hang in there. -Stevens talk to him. -I'm--I'm sorry.
格蕾 他的血压多少
Okay Grey how is his pressure?
收缩压85 开始静脉注射
85 systolic. Open up his I.V.
斯蒂文斯 和他说话 帮帮他
Stevens talk to him! Help him!
斯蒂文斯 让他咳嗽 让他呼吸 斯蒂文斯
Stevens get him to cough get him to breathe. Stevens!
血压稳定了
Pressure's stabilizing.
好的 还好吗 麦克
Okay how you doing mike?
还是 不能呼吸
I still... can't breathe.
这是不是意味着失败了
Does that mean we're not successful?
麦克 有两条可选动脉路径
Mike there were two arterial routes I could choose.
下一次做的时候 我觉得
The next time we do this I think--
不 我不行 我再也不做了
No I can't. I won't do this again.
求求你 我真的做不了
Please I can't-- I can't do this again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真是对不起
I'so sorry.
告诉斯蒂文斯来见我
Tell Stevens to find me
我要永远把她踢出我的手术
So I can permanently throw her off my service.
翰医生 我知道你和这个病人交情深
Dr. Hahn I know you have a history with this patient
-从某种角度伊兹也是 -她和我的病人有交情
-But in a weird way Izzie does too. -A history with my patient?
不是的 是和丹尼·杜奎特
No with Denny duquette.
叫她来找我
Tell her to find me.
肿瘤转移了
The tumor's position has been altered.
我需要超声定位
I need an ultrasound localization.
顺便提一句 我把杨的问题解决了
Took care of my Yang problem by the way.
已经解决了
Already?
听起来很容易嘛
That sounds too easy.
如果觉得不可能 就肯定不可能
If it doesn't feel like work it's not going to work.
你从哪里学来的 婚姻咨询
Where'd you learn that hmm marriage counseling?
当然不是 那纯粹是在浪费时间
Of course not. It's a complete waste of time.
波得夫妇
This couple the Bullards
我打赌他们从来没有做过婚姻咨询
I bet they never got counseling.
他们能彼此接受对方的好与坏
They just take their bad with the good.
该死
Damn it.
肿瘤出血了 她开始脑肿了
The tumor's hemorrhaging. Her brain's starting to swell.
注射70毫升甘露醇 心跳过缓 1毫升阿托品
Push 70 of the mannitol. She's bradying down. Uh 1 of atropine.
我们得保证这对夫妇再相聚啊
Let's make sure these two get a chance to say hello again.
看见伊兹了吗
Have you seen Izzie?
没 你那儿有我能参加的手术吗
No. You got anything I can scrub in on?
机器病人烂死了
Robo patient sucks.
听着 伊兹今天很惨
Listen Izzie is having a rough day
-如果你见到她 -不不不 我才惨呢
-So if you see her don't- -No no no I'm having a rough day.
怎么了
What happened?
亨特 亨特讨厌我 我是说 他恨我
Hunt. Hunt hates me. I mean he hates me.
他吻过你啊
He kissed you.
是啊 那是 我不知道 过去的事情
Yes uh that was I don't know before.
他现在恨我入骨 比翰更恨我
Now he hates my guts. This is worse than Hahn.
我是说 我都不知道我说错或是做错了什么
I mean i-I have no idea what I did or--Or said or what...
我要甩了这个病例
I gotta get off this case.
杨医生 病人的手术预定好了
Dr. Yang... our guy is scheduled for surgery
-我想知道什么时候才能再见你 -他还不稳定
-And I want to know when I'm gonna see you next. -Uh he's not stable yet.
我们可以一起去
Oh. Well then we might have time to--
有人呼我
Uh I just got paged down.
我的挑战来了
This does not happen to me.
向我致敬吧 我是实习女王
Bow to me for I am the queen of the interns.
我集合了死亡军团来教我们
I have assembled an army of the dead to teach us things.
尸体
Cadavers--
我找到了可以练习的尸体 超多尸体
I got us cadavers to practice on a whole bunch of 'em.
-尸体 人尸 -在下面的停尸房 午饭那里会合
-You got cadavers human cadavers? -They're down in the tunnels. We'll meet there for lunch.
好的
Okay.
问你点事
-Let me ask you something. -Hmm?
你知道伊兹·斯蒂文斯和丹尼·杜奎特
Do you know if Izzie Stevens had some sort of a relationship
的关系吗
With Denny duquette?
什么 除了订婚吗
What you mean besides the engagement
还有剪断左心室装置电线
Oh and the cutting of his l-Vad wire
好让他在移植等待名单中靠前一点
So she could move him up the transplant list?
什么 你都不知道嘛
What you didn't know about this?
伊兹被留职察看
Izzie was on probationary leave.
她差点被开除
She was like nearly kicked out of the program.
-我忘了你当时还没来 -我的确没来
-I forget you weren't here then. -No I wasn't.
我在另外一家医院眼睁睁看着我的病人
I was at another hospital watching my patient's heart
心脏被人偷走
Get stolen out of his chest.
你呼我下来做爱吗
Did you page me down here for sex?
我现在没那个心情
Because I'm not really in the mood.
-想看看死人吗 -什么
-Want to see some dead guys? -Why?
-过来 -为什么那么说 为什么
-Come on. -Why would you say that? Why?
尸体
Cadavers...
-练习用的 -什么
-For practice... -what?
-为了主刀手术 -这是干什么
-For the solo surgery. -What is this?
听说你今天很倒霉
I heard you were having a crappy day.
我想用这个给你鼓鼓劲
I thought this would cheer you up.
怎么了
What?
就像你送了我一束尸体编扎得花束
It's like a bouquet of corpses.
这太 不好意思
That is so um I'm sorry.
不 这太疯狂了 他已经死了
No. That's crazy. He's dead.
他死了 今天居然这么多死人
He is dead. Just so many dead people today.
这是给实习生用的
These are for interns.
去用模型练习
Go play with the dummy!
拜托
Ah come on!
我没办法 我要死了
I cannot help it. I'm dying.
-我在加压了 -你肯定忘了什么
-But I'm applying pressure -There must be something you're forgetting.
别叫
Oh Dont crying out loud!
真不敢相信你居然通过了实习生考试
I'm surprised you even passed your intern exam.
上帝啊
Oh my god.
不好意思 忍不住
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
主任 我有话跟你说
Chief I have to talk to you.
翰 进来 来看看这个
Hey Hahn. Come in. I want you to watch this.
会让你喷饭的
Let's blow an artery.
我出血了 我出血了
I'm bleeding out. I'm bleeding out.
是伊兹和丹尼·杜奎特的事
It's about Izzie Stevens and Denny duquette.
怎么斯蒂文斯还在这儿工作
How is Stevens still working here?
西雅图圣恩居然还有医院资质
How is Seattle Grace still accredited?
这件事就没有上报吗
This whole thing goes unreported?
难怪这医院只能排12名
It's no wonder this place is number 12.
你这是家什么医院呀
What kind of hospital are you running?
适可而止 爱瑞克
You want to stop right there Erica.
我要求组织医德评估小组介入调查
I want an ethics review panel assembled.
我要让大家知道斯蒂文斯干了什么
I want Stevens' role in this investigated
还有贝利 她是伊兹的上级
And Bailey's as well because she was her superior.
别这样 爱瑞克
Slow down Erica.
我的病人为此失去了一颗心脏 理查德
No. My patient lost a heart over this Richard!
-这个人必须为此滚蛋 -够了
- Someone is damn well gonna lose their job. - Stop!
我不打算旧事重提 这件事没有隐瞒不报的
We're not digging this up. It didn't go unreported.
他们向我报告了 是我这么处理的
It was reported to me. I dealt with it.
斯蒂文斯受到了惩罚 她已经改了
Stevens was punished. She's learned from her mistake.
她现在正在成长为一名优秀的外科医生
And she is on her way to becoming an excellent surgeon.
这就是我们医院的管理方式
That's the kind of hospital I'm running.
这件事已经尘封了
Now this issue has been laid to rest.
这是过去的事儿 我不会再挖出来
It's in the past and that's where it's gonna stay.
可对我来说不是过去的事
It is not in the past for me.
他正躺在重症室里 生命垂危
It's lying on a bed in the I.C.U. About to die.
那你的责任就是确保
Then your only responsibility is to make sure
他不会死
that doesn't happen.
手术进行得很艰难
It was a difficult surgery
特别是对她这个年龄的人
Especially at her age.
无法知道她能否好转
We're not sure how she's gonna respond.
我知道 当然
Oh sure.
等待总是最难熬的
The waiting is always the hard part.
埃德 她也许过不了今晚
Ed she might not make it through the night.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
伊兹
Iz.
你在躲着翰
You hiding from Hahn?
当然 也包括她
Sure. Her too.
麦克情况好吗
Is Mike okay?
不好 烧灼术失败
No the ablation failed.
他不愿做第二次 所以翰
And he's refusing to try again so Hahn's...
你该去找她谈谈
Um you should go talk to her.
我偷走了他的心脏 梅丽迪斯
I stole his heart Meredith.
为了丹尼 为了我自己
I stole it for Denny. I stole it for myself.
现在我们折磨他时 却要我握着他的手
And now I'm supposed to hold his hand while we torture him?
我都没法看着他
I can't even look at him.
他在这儿是我的过错造成的
It's my fault that he's here.
所以 我得躲着他
So anyway... I'm hiding.
杨 请抽吸这里
Yang suction here please.
斯隆马上来做鄂修复术了吗
Sloan's coming in for the mandibular repair?
刚才的事我很抱歉
Sorry about before.
这里每个人都爱管别人的闲事
Everybody's uh up in everybody else's business around here you know?
请你说话专业点
Better to keep things professional if you can.
你和他们一起工作
Yes. Because one minute you're working with people
然后成为朋友 甚至密友
And then you're friends with them and then you're whatever
突然有些人站出来
And then suddenly there's all this pressure
非黑即白得来评论你
To define what you are like it's all black-and-white.
非要评出个对错来
You're either this or you're that.
你知道自己老毛病又犯了是吧
You are aware that you're doing it again right?
亨特医生 咱们的病人怎样了
Dr. Hunt how's our mystery man?
很稳定 他壮得很
Still with us. He's a fighter.
不能一起去休息室活动真不爽 凯丽
Hate to be the other guy. Callie.
杨医生 我知道你更喜欢开胸
Dr. Yang I know cracking chests is more your thing
但你看我处理完他的皮肤以后
But you'd be surprised how exciting it can be
你一定会兴奋不已
When I manipulate a little skin.
杨医生 我觉得你可以离开了
Actually Dr. Yang why don't you just scrub out?
我们这里人手够了
We've got enough hands in here.
好吧
Okay.
我听说他醒了 我能进手术室吗
Oh hey. I heard he went up. Can I scrub in?
闭嘴 我没份 你也没份
Oh shut it. If I'm not in you're not in.
-你好臭啊 -我洗澡了
-God you stink. - I showered.
你身上一股甲醛味 就像死人的味道
You smell like formaldehyde. Why do you smell like death?
为什么你身上有死人的味道
Why do you smell like death?
好多死人啊
I see dead people.
-出去 -我需要避开亨特
- Get out. -I need off my Hunt case
所以给你一次机会
so in a one-time-only offer
我跟你做个交易
I'm gonna trade you
我那被打得半死的重伤病人
My beaten-to-a-pulp traumapalooza patient
换至少三具尸体
For no less than uh three of your cadavers.
快点决定
Pony up.
成交 给你三个
Deal take three.
我需要跟人呆在一起
I need to be with people--
最好是活人 不过
Preferably live people-- But whatever.
对了 阿历克斯
Alex by the way
谢谢你给我找来这些尸体
Thank you for bringing me the corpses.
你真好心
It was very sweet.
亨特和斯隆医生还在做手术
Dr. Hunt and Dr. Sloan are still operating.
你们觉得我是否
Do you think I could try--
不行
No.
看看这个 我去世的母亲教我
Hey so check this out my dead mommy taught me
一种很酷的拿刀手法
a cool way to hold these instruments.
用手掌来握 这样换刀更快些
If you palm it you can switch off faster.
你去世的母亲教你时 你能看到她吗
When your dead mommy teaches you things can you see her?
不 我是读她日记学来的
No. I'm reading her journals.
当然不会 我开玩笑的
Duh. I was kidding... obviously.
我的确见到过她一次 还有那个拆弹警察
I did see her once though and that bomb squad guy...
还有丹尼
And Denny.
今天看见的
Today?
不 我差点死了的那次
No. I was dead at the time.
有时我还能感觉到我的母亲
I still feel my mom with me sometimes.
我得退出这个病例
I gotta get off this case.
-我能不能 -不能
- Could I-- - No.
拜托 别在里面 拜托 别在里面
Please don't be in there. Please don't be in there.
拜托 别在里面
Please don't be in there.
翰医生 我向你道歉
Dr. Hahn I came to apologize
我能不能调离这个病例
and ask if I could please be let off your service.
不行
No.
如果我能让麦克再进行一次手术
If I can convince Mike to have another ablation
你得在他一旁陪着
You're gonna be there to see him through
看着他的眼睛
to look him in the eye
帮他渡过痛苦 你带给他的痛苦
To help him through the pain that you have caused him.
如果他死了 你也得在场
And if he dies I want you there for that too
因为是你造成的
Because you're responsible.
他决定了
He decided.
他不接受第二次手术
He won't do another procedure.
我现在去
I'm going to...
帮他办出院手续
Go check him out.
斯蒂文斯医生
Dr. Stevens...
她会没事的
She'll be okay.
这
This has...
这已经不是第一次了
This has been coming for a long time.
她不会有事的 她
She'll be okay. She'll...
她会好好生活下去的
She'll move on.
如果你死了
If you die...
她不会好过的
She will not get over it.
她不可能好好生活下去
She will not move on.
她会觉得可以 甚至觉得自己已经克服了
She'll think she can she'll even think she has
但是 也许某一天 你会出现在她身边
And then... out of the blue you'll be right there with her
离得那么近 她甚至觉得能触碰到你
So close she'll think she can touch you
而这种感觉
And then all of this will just...
将会一次次得缠着她
Be happening for her all over again.
她将无法摆脱
And she will not be able to move on.
他们什么都不做
They're--They're not doing anything.
让他们动起来 他们只是站在一旁
Make them do something. They're just standing around.
波得先生 他们这样是想让她舒服些
Mr. Bullard they're keeping her comfortable.
他们能做的只有这么多了
That's all they can do.
你和罗斯同意的
You and Rosie agreed
如果她时间到了 我们不会实施急救
There would be no extreme measures taken if her time came.
现在 她的时间到了
Well her time is here.
发生什么事
What's going on?
她快不行了 而波得先生想撤销
Uh she's coding and Mr. Bullard is reconsidering
不予急救医嘱
The D.N.R. Order.
埃德 我提醒你的就是这情况
Ed this is what I warned you about
此刻
This moment.
即使我们抢救她
Even if we try to resuscitate her
她也不一定能醒过来
I'm not sure she's gonna wake up again.
我们能做的只有这些了
Nothing more we can do.
罗斯
Rosie.
罗斯?
Rosie?
亲爱的
Honey?
罗斯?
Rosie?
不
No.
不 别离开我 罗斯
No. Stay with me Rosie.
罗斯?
Rosie?
别走 别离开我 罗斯
Stay with me. Don't leave me Rosie.
别走 罗斯 别离开我
Stay with me Rosie. Don't leave me.
别离开我 罗斯
Stay with me. Stay with me Rosie.
别离开我 回来 罗斯
Stay with me. Come back Rosie.
别走 别离开我
Don't leave me. Stay with me.
别离开我
Don't leave me.
别走 别离开我 罗斯
Stay with me. Don't leave me Rosie.
别离开我 罗斯
Stay with me Rosie.
别走 不要离开我
Don't leave me. Stay with me. Don't leave me.
别走 罗斯 别离开我
Stay with me Rosie. Stay with me.
别这样 波得先生
No... Mr. Bullard...
那就救救她 救救她
Do something for her then. Do something.
对不起 波得先生
I'm so sorry. Mr. Bullard.
-不 不 -放手吧
-No! No! - Now--Just--
由着他吧 别拦他
Let him be. Let him be.
求你了 罗斯 求你了
Please Rosie. Please.
很高兴你决定再试一次
I'm glad you decided to try again.
多亏了斯蒂文斯医生
You can thank Dr. Stevens.
我们在这里是她造成的 不是吗
It's her fault we're here right?
体征稳定 可以开始注射了
Vitals are stable. He's ready for the injection.
好的 开始注射酒精
All right. Alcohol is going in.
等等 别
Oh wait. Wait don't. Oh.
麦克 看着我 陪在我身边
Mike look at me. Just stay with me.
肯定会疼的
It's going to hurt
但不如你想象的那么疼
But not as much as you think it's going to.
室上性心动过速
Okay he's in S.V.T.
可能有些酒精倒流入A.V.节点了
There may be alcohol backing into his A.V. Node.
让他咳嗽 让他呼吸
Get him to cough. Get him to breathe.
麦克 你需要呼吸
Mike you need to breathe.
用力咳嗽 看着我 麦克
Cough for me. Look at me Mike.
看着我
Look at me.
室性心动过速 病人快失去知觉了
He's in V-Tach losing consciousness.
静推100毫升利多卡因
All right push 100 of lidocaine.
准备好调搏器
Get the pacer ready.
拜托
Oh man.
莱西呼我
It's Lexie.
我得走了 被揍得半死的家伙快不行了
I gotta go. Beaten-to-a-pulp guy is coding.
不
Oh No.
那家伙是我的 我们交换过了
Pulp guy is mine. We traded.
为什么不给他插胸管
Why didn't you put in a chest tube?
我 我不会
Well I was-- I don't know how.
你不会是什么意思
What do you mean you don't know how?
我来这儿的第一周就学会了
I mean I learned that in my first week.
是的 你学会了 你懂
Yes you learned you know.
可我永远都懂不了
But I will never know
因为你不仅不让我自己尝试
Because you not only won't let me try one
你连我们的实验机器人和尸体都抢走了
But you--You hog all our robots and you steal our corpses.
老妹 你把她逼疯了
Dude I think you broke her.
体征暂时稳定了
Vitals are stable for now.
之前他的尿里也有这么多血吗
Was there this much blood in his urine before?
没有
No.
-他得做个侧向膀胱造影 -实习生已经去准备了
-he's gonna need a bedside cystogram. -Dibs on that.
不 不 这个我来做 膀胱造影也由我负责
No, no, it's mine and his bladder repair is mine, too.
不 我们有交易
No, we traded for him.
不 我们可没拿此做交换
No, no, you see we never traded
此外 3号 为了证明你是错的
and just to prove you wrong 3
下次这人再昏厥 你插这根胸管
Next time this guy crashes you put in this chest tube.
全都给我滚开 离病人远点
Get away from that man right now.
他刚才不行了 我们注射了多巴胺 并且...
Uh, he was crashing. so we upped his dopamine and gave
你聋了吗 克莱夫 我说了离他远点
Are you deaf, Karev? I said step away from him.
我们正在救他啊
I'm just saying that we were saving his life.
不 你们把它当动物一样来对待
No, what you did was pick over him like vultures
像是一群无知的小孩在争抢玩具
like a bunch of children fighting over toys.
你们争抢病人的所做所为
What you did was treat a man that's fighting to live
好象他早死了一样
As if he's already dead.
你们没有任何判断力 不严谨 丝毫没有尊重
You have no sense no decency and no respect!
滚开
Just get out.
离开这里
Just get out of here.
埃德
Ed...
罗斯 玛丽 已经去了
Rosemary's gone.
她的心脏再也不会自己跳动了
Her heart is no longer beating on its own.
在你停止按压的那一刻起
The second you stop doing what you're doing
它就停跳了
It will stop.
我不能让她在我面前走掉
I-I can't be the one... to let her go...
让她死了
To let her die.
我知道
I know.
我知道你不能
I know you can't.
过来 坐下 坐下
Here you go. Sit down. Sit down.
请坐
Sit down.
贝利医生
Dr. Bailey.
麦克
Mike...
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
留下来陪着我
Just stay here with me.
我要你战斗起来 麦克
I need you to fight, mike.
为了和伊兹相伴 而战斗
Fight to stay with Izzie.
你必须这么做 呼吸起来
You have to do this. You need to breathe right now.
马上 马上
Right now! Right now!
你没事了
You're okay.
没事了
你不用这样
You don't have to do it.
让我来
Let me. Let me.
杨医生
Dr. Yang
我要你今晚给我把那份
I'll need you to bring me the post-Op report
有关我们病人的手术报告拿来
On our beating victim before you leave tonight.
对不起 对不起 你刚才有说话吗
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Did you say something?
杨 你是怎么了
Yang what is wrong with you?
先生
Sir?
有个女人要做手术
I've had women opt
是那种不必要的故意提臀术
For needless elective buttock enhancement surgery
其实是要跟我调情而已
Just for another chance to be flirted with by me.
你到底怎么了
So what's your deal?
我不知道你究竟在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking out.
我整天都在挑逗你
I've been hitting on you all day.
噢
Oh.
我...真的吗
I... really?
不好意思
Excuse me.
真是个愚蠢的主意
It was a stupid idea.
不是我的主意 是谢博德在搞鬼
It wasn't even my idea. It was Shepherd's idea.
-哦 拜托 -这个女人连一瓶苏格兰酒都比不上
-Oh, come on -That woman isn't a single malt scotch
伙计 她是瓶馊了的廉价酒
my friend, she is bad cheap wine
让你头疼 疼到牙缝里
That gives you a headache you can feel in your teeth.
亨特医生 今天有没有对明年计划的设想
Dr. Hunt. Any thoughts on the second years after today?
我来了才一天 主任
It's only been a day, sir.
当然
of course
他们无法调教 不知所云
They're undisciplined, inarticulate
连起码的尊重都不懂
And they have a lot to learn about respect.
大多数人只为
Mostly, they're more interested
一己之私利而工作
In their personal crap than in anything else
看不出他们是被好好教过的
I'm not sure that they're being taught anything different.
老实说 我还没决定是否要留下
Honestly, I'm not sure I'll be staying on.
告辞 主任
Excuse me, sir.
告诉我 这一切不是真的
Tell me I am not seeing what I'm seeing.
别告诉我 这是真的
Tell me I am not seeing
满屋子的尸体
A roomful of human bodies
到处乱放 半开着体腔 无人管理
Half-Open scattered and forgotten about.
他们没有人认领
They're unclaimed bodies.
无人认领
Unclaimed?
他们每一个人都曾被爱过
Each of one of these people was loved.
每一个人都可能是某人的至爱
Each one of these people was somebody's somebody
我们有责任将他们好好对待
So we are responsible for treating them as such.
而我们却用这种所谓的尊重来收容他们
We claim them and treat them with respect!
把他们缝合好 盖好
Close them up cover them up
放回原来的位置
And put them back where they belong.
马上
Now!
那个病人的太太来了
Oh. The wife's here of the beating victim.
她认出她丈夫了 想要...
She I.D. her husband, so she wanted to
他名字叫什么
What's his name?
我想知道 你是否知道她丈夫的名字
I wondered if you asked her her husband's name
使他在你面前起码是个人
So that he could become a person to you.
他们都是人啊 杨
They're all people Yang.
这不是用来决定由谁执刀的
This is not a game or a contest or a competition
什么游戏 比赛或是竞争
To see who gets a surgery and who doesn't.
他们是人 我们救死扶伤
They're people and we get to save them.
你很优秀 你很棒
Now you're good. You're excellent.
你能赢得所有的竞争
You could win all the contests
但作为医生 你不能如此轻浮
But if that's why you're doing this then you shouldn't be.
先把病人名字找出来
So did you find out his name?
我父亲在我9岁时 在一场车祸中死了
My dad died when I was 9 in a car accident.
我就在车里
I was with him in the car.
在我们等救护车的时候
While we waited for the ambulance
我努力把他的胸腔合上
I tried to keep his chest closed
希望能少流点血
So he wouldn't bleed so much.
在他死的时候
When he died...
我亲手感受到了他心脏停止跳动的瞬间
My hands... felt his heart stop beating.
这就是为何我做医生
That's why I do this.
也是为什么我总比别人棒
It's also why I win all the contests.
病人的名字叫汤姆
The patient's name is tom.
单身苏格兰麦牙酒
Single malt scotch.
我们出生 生存 死亡
We're born, we live, we die.
有时并不按那个顺序来
Sometimes not necessarily in that order.
注意
Clear!
哇 你不用死了
Yes! You don't get to die!
做得好
Nice job.
谢谢 我...
Thanks. I uh...
他只是个机器人
You know he's just a robot.
我要收回我刚才说的 关于离开
I want to take back what I said before about leaving
我反应过度了
I was overreacting.
我当时... 有点私人情绪
I was just... it was personal
希望你忘了我所说的一切
And I wondered if you could just forget about it.
睡一觉吧 hunt医生 明天见
Get some sleep Dr. Hunt. See you tomorrow.
主任
Chief?
真棒 欧麦利医生
Good save O'malley.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们把心绪放到一边
We put things to rest...
除非有必要再次激发
Only to have them rise up again.
我也参加
I'm in.
"于是那天就以一个部分结肠切除术而告终"
"So I ended my day with a segmental colectomy."
哦 烂人来了
Oh, badass.
哦 斯隆 真的假的
Oh Sloan? Seriously?
怎么 你以为是双人约会吗
What? Oh did you think we'd double-Date?
我马上要脱下我的裤子了
Look, I'm gonna take my pants off
-除非你想留下看 -不
-So unless you want to stay and see. -Nope.
我晚些再看
I'll see it later.
先去楼下了
I'm gonna go downstairs.
所以死亡并不是终点
So if death is not the end
看你是否认为有价值
What can you count on anymore?
你的病人怎样了
So how's your patient doing?
他还是在等心脏 我某天会为他买一个
Well, he still needs a heart but I bought him some time.
真好 我很高兴
Good, I'm glad.
我去主任那里问伊兹·斯蒂文斯的事
I went to the chief about Izzie Stevens
他完全不让我插手此事
And he completely shut me down.
我要看看 等我向卫生部报告后 他还能说什么
we'll see what he says when I report this to u.N.O.S.
哦 哦 等等 为什么 你说什么
Whoa. Whoa whoa whoa. Wait why? What...
-怎么突然有这念头 -你什么意思
-What good would come of that? -What do you mean?
这样做有什么好处
What possible good would it do?
对你病人又有什么好处呢
I mean would it benefit your patient's outcome
要是心脏没被她拿走 我病人今天就不会来这里
My patient wouldn't be here if it wasn't for her.
那你要把这事报告卫生部
So you're gonna report this to u.N.O.S.
让医院的行医执照给吊销
And cost this hospital its transplant certification
病人的器官 大家的工作都付出代价
Cost our patients organs cost people their jobs
让伊兹·斯蒂文斯断送前程
Cost Izzie Stevens her career?
那这件事上你站在伊兹这一边 不理我的感受
so you're taking Izzie Stevens' side in this over mine
她是个医生 是我们中的一员
She's a doctor. one of our doctors.
互相扶持是很有必要的
There's a reason we have each others' backs
不要用这种调调跟我说话
please do not talk to me about a code
-根本不是那么回事 -不 就是这么回事
-Because this is not that. -No, this is that.
我不知道在丹尼·杜奎特
Look, I don't know what happened
和伊兹·斯蒂文斯之间 那晚究竟发生了什么
Between Denny duquette and Izzie Stevens that night
但除非你当时完全是局外人的身份
But unless you were in the middle of that situation
不然你没有资格来做评判
I don't see how you can make a judgment.
问题很简单 就是对与错
Easy. There's right and there's wrong.
而这是错误的 非法的
And this was wrong and illegal.
这里没有灰色地带
There is no gray area here.
你不能觉得这事貌似没关系
You can't kind of think this is okay.
不能貌似站到了伊兹·斯蒂文斯那边去
You can't kind of side with Izzie Stevens.
你也不能貌似是个女同志
And you can't kind of be a lesbian.
是的 我可以
Yes, I can.
因为你无法指望生活中的任何事
Because you sure can't count on anything in life.
我无法相信我居然不知道
I can't believe I didn't know this.
爱瑞卡 主任是对的
Erica, the chief is right.
我根本不了解你
I don't know you at all.
生活 是最脆弱 最不稳定
Life is the most fragile unstable
最变幻莫测的事情
Unpredictable thing there is.
不 不
No. No.
你不能过来
You can't be here.
我必须振作起来 我...
I have to move on. I...
我爱你 我一直都很爱你
I love you and I will always love you
但我必须将生活继续
But I have to move on.
因此我今天面对了那个病人
That's why I had that patient today
因此我今天参与对他的救助
And that's... why I helped save his life
才能减轻我的内疚感
So that I wouldn't feel guilty anymore
这样才能继续前行
And I can move on.
所以 请你
So please...
你必须走
You have to go.
去哪
Go where?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
我完全没事
I am totally okay.
我很好 一切都很好
I'm fine. Everything's fine.
我换衣服了
I have to change
在酒吧等你 好吗
But I'll meet you at the bar , okay?
-好吧 -好的
-All right. -Okay.
事实上 关于生活 只有一件事情我们可以确定
In fact, there's only one thing about life we can be sure of...
你确定你没事吗
Are you sure you're okay?